Please stay safe, Rin, Shirou!
Unlimited Blade Works
Is that all you have?
As I thought, you were a fake.
You are incapable of saving anything.
That shabby Archer said as much, did he not?
That your ideals were not your own.
I'm astonished that a man without a thing to call his own
was arrogant enough to think he could accomplish anything.
"Champion of justice"?
"A world where no one is hurt"?
Don't be absurd.
"Humanity" is the name for beasts that cannot find joy in life without sacrifice.
Your much-vaunted "equality" is nonsense spouted
by weaklings who cannot bear to stare into the abyss.
It is naught but an excuse to cover up your own ugliness.
Yeah, he's exactly right.
My desires are borrowed.
A pretense I put on, copied from someone I once saw saving another.
When it happened, I was empty inside.
Everyone was dying indiscriminately,
and nobody looked to save anyone else.
If I hadn't resigned myself to the idea that that's how people are,
I wouldn't have been able to keep on living.
That's why...
That's precisely why I was inspired by his ideal.
Is that so wrong?
Are these feelings fake just because they aren't my own?
Should I not achieve that ideal, just because it's fake?
No.
I know that's not right.
It doesn't matter if it's fake. Or an unattainable wish.
I know that I can't save everyone.
I know that no one can be saved without sacrifice!
Even knowing that it was nothing but an ideal,
I only chased after it even harder.
Even if I hurt one to save many,
I'll keep pursuing a happy future where no one will be hurt.
And this is where that ideal ultimately lead him.
A man once told me that what I believed in—
what I still believe in—was hypocrisy.
But in spite of that,
the man who said those words
stayed true to that same hypocrisy to the end.
Which means that I can do it.
Even if it's borrowed, even if it's fake, I don't care.
I'm okay with that.
Emiya Shirou can keep striving toward this dream!
Even if he doesn't find a single thing he was searching for!
Come on...
That's all there was to it?
Though I may have held back,
I'm sure you felt the blast of wind from Ea.
If you have all those weapons,
why would you hold back just one?
Only the supreme ruler may wield that blade.
You haven't the right to so much as look upon it.
Saber...
Are you unharmed, Shirou?
I shall take over from here.
No, you go help Tohsaka.
I can handle Gilgamesh by myself.
What are you saying, Shirou?
A mage is no match for a Servant.
Yeah, but he and I are exceptions to the rules.
Trust me.
I know I can beat this guy!
Good luck.
I shall keep Rin safe.
Saber...
I wasn't able to save you.
I think that Grail isn't what you were hoping for.
So take a good look.
To make sure that you get it right next time.
Shirou?
Sorry, it's hard to explain.
I guess I was never cut out to be your Master.
So...
That is untrue.
You are my Master, Shirou.
I shall go fulfill my duty as a Servant.
Let us continue our discussion afterward.
Are you mad, boy?
You choose to be the sacrificial pawn, rather than use Saber?
You fool.
The act of self-sacrifice is naught but a lie.
Being unable to see that, even now,
marks you as an incorrigible hypocrite.
A fraud and a hypocrite, huh?
I guess. I am a fake through and through, after all.
But I was mistaken all along.
My sword-making doesn't actually create them.
There's only one thing that I can do.
And that's to give form to what's in my mind.
I am the bone of my sword!
Steel is my body and fire is my blood
I have created over a thousand blades
Unaware of Loss,
nor aware of Gain
Withstood pain to create weapons,
waiting for one’s arrival
I have no regrets. This is the only path
My whole life was Unlimited Blade Works!
That's right. I don't create swords.
I create a world that contains an unlimited number of swords.
That is the only magic allowed to Emiya Shirou.
A Reality Marble, eh?
What of it?
What can you do with this wretched mental landscape?
Don't be so surprised.
Everything here is a fake.
However, there's nothing that says a fake can't rival the real thing.
If you say you're the genuine article,
then I'll just surpass everything about you and take you down.
Here I come, King of Heroes.
Do you have enough weapons in stock?
You think too highly of yourself, mongrel.
What in the world is that?
Can being summoned incorrectly change a Servant so drastically?
Rin!
Where are you, Rin?
Saber?
Rin!
No, Saber!
But...
Trust me. Just don't.
This muck is similar to a Servant in nature.
If you touched it, there's no telling what would happen.
I understand.
Then hurry to this side, Rin.
As long as you can get clear, I shall see to the rest.
Yeah. Okay, I'll leave it to you.
But if I don't get there in time, do what has to be done.
I cannot, Rin!
If that is the alternative, I shall rescue you now!
These curses are...
Rin! You used a Command Spell?
Of course I did.
I can't let the one person who can
destroy the Grail throw her life away.
Besides, you don't need to worry about me.
I can get out of this, no problem.
So don't worry about that.
Just believe in me and ready your holy sword.
Rin...
If only.
This is definitely easier said than done.
I wonder if this thing would let me go if I returned Shinji.
What's happening?
That's...
Rin!
Oh, no.
Why are this mongrel's blades giving me pause?
Don't you get it?
You may be ranked the highest of all Heroic Spirits
because you possess over a thousand Noble Phantasms.
But you're a king, not a warrior.
You didn't choose the path of mastering a single Noble Phantasm.
You're like me: jack of all trades, master of none!
When I'm done with you, there won't be a single bone shard left of your counterfeiting cranium!
This is the pits.
I can't even tell which way to go to get out of here.
That jerk sure is using up my mana.
This is it, I guess.
But I won't let it end like this.
By my Command Spell, I order you:
Saber, destroy the Holy Grail right now!
What? Impossible!
Rin! Get out of there!
Sorry, Saber.
You probably wouldn't do it if I just asked you, so I have to force you.
And I guess I should apologize to you too.
Sorry I couldn't save you, Shinji.
Your pathetic whining offends me.
Now go, Rin.
Hurry, Rin!
Saber!
I'm feeding you the last of my mana!
So take that Holy Grail
and blast it so hard
there won't be a single trace left!
Ex...
calibur!
Wow...
Our contract is concluded.
Victory is yours, Rin.
Were it allowed, I would have liked to have remained to the end
to see what becomes of you two.
However, that is not my role.
After all, Shirou has you, Rin.
Impossible!
I'm being forced back?
By a fraud like you?
Against any other Servant,
creating a world like this wouldn't let me hold my own.
Having an unlimited number of swords
wouldn't let me stand up to a Servant who had mastered one!
But against you,
my swords are ready and waiting,
so I'm always one step ahead!
D-Damn you...
Damn you!
Damn you! Damn you!
To think that I must go all-out against the likes of you!
Rho Aias.
I shall grant you this:
at this moment, you are powerful!
You're not getting away!
You ran out of mana? How anticlimactic.
Victory is yours.
Die with that satisfaction, faker.
What?
Swallowing me accomplishes nothing...
Wait!
The Holy Grail's hole?
That malformed abomination!
Does it not know that a fellow Servant cannot be made its core?
Damn...
You're trying to take me down with you?
Fool!
I haven't the least intention of dying!
Plant your heels, ruffian!
At least until I climb back to where you are!
As if!
I'll rip off my own arm if that's what it takes!
Do so if you wish, but step to the right first.
You—
Ar... cher...
That guy...
Always showing off.
Archer!
Archer...
It's unfortunate,
but there you have it.
Give up on the Grail this time, Rin.
What's with that?
This is hardly the time to be laughing!
My apologies.
I couldn't help it, given your state.
I was amused that you and I cut such sorry figures.
Archer... Will you make a contract with me again?
I can't do that.
I doubt I have that right.
Besides, I no longer have a goal.
My battle ends here.
But... But this means you'll...
No matter how much time passes, you'll never be saved.
Oh, man.
Rin.
Look after me.
As you know, I'm a bit hopeless.
Give me a shoulder to lean on.
Archer...
Yeah, I know.
I'll do my best.
I'll try my hardest to make sure
he doesn't end up a twisted jerk like you.
I'll make sure he learns to love himself!
So you hang in there too!
I have my answer.
Don't worry, Tohsaka.
I'll try my hardest from now on, too.
Damn, I didn't even get the chance to tear him a new one.
Let's go home, Tohsaka.
Epilogue
Next Time